救命啊！
Help!
有人么？
Anyone?
救命啊！
Help!
你好，麦克
Hello, Michael.
我想和你玩个游戏
I want to play a game.
到目前为止，在你所谓的一生里
So far, in what could loosely be called your life,
你一直通过窥探他人而谋生
you've made a living watching others.
社会上称你为告密者、小人和小贼
Society would call you an informant, a rat, a snitch.
我说你配不上自己的躯体
I call you unworthy of the body you possess,
和被赋予的生命
of the life that you've been given.
现在，让我们看看你是否愿意注重内心
Now we will see if you are willing to look inward.
而不是外表
rather than outward,
放弃你依赖的东西
to give up the one thing you rely on in order to go on living.
你脖子上的装置叫做死亡面具
The device around your neck is a death mask.
它由弹簧控制器控制
The mask is on a spring timer.
如果你不能及时找到钥匙
If you do not locate the key in time,
面具就会关上
the mask will close.
你可以把它想象成捕蝇草一样的东西
Think of it like a Venus flytrap.
你现在看到的是不到2小时前
What you are looking at right now is your own body.
- 你自己的身体 - 哦，妈的
- not more than two hours ago. - Oh, fuck.
别担心 你睡着了什么感觉都没有
Don't worry. You're sound asleep and can't feel a thing.
考虑到你如今处于完全的劣势
Taking into account that you are at a great disadvantage here,
我会提示你钥匙被藏在哪里了
I am going to give you a hint as to where I've hidden the key.
现在听好了
So listen carefully.
提示就是…
The hint is this.
它就在你眼睛前面
It's right before your eyes.
麦克，为了生存你要流多少血？
How much blood will you shed to stay alive, Michael?
生还是死
Live or die.
你自己选择
Make your choice.
你他妈的到底是谁？ 你他妈的到底是谁？
Who the fuck are you? Who the fuck are you?
你他妈的到底是谁？
Who the fuck are you?
不！
Fuck! No!
不要！
No!
来人救救我啊！
Someone help me!
妈的！
Oh, fuck!
照做！
Do it.
妈的！
Oh, fuck!
救命！
Help me!
求你了！
Help me! Please!
妈的！
Fuck! What the fuck?
拜托！
Please!
不，不，不，不！
No, no, no, no, no, no!
《电锯惊魂2》
- 打扰了 - 什么事？
- Excuse me. - Help you?
我来找丹尼·马修的
I'm here for Daniel Matthews.
在这签名
Sign these.
谢谢，我们走，丹尼
Thanks. Let's go, Daniel.
你来得够晚的
Took you long enough.
抱歉没把这事记在日程上
I'm sorry I didn't have it penciled in on my schedule.
- 你知道他们会控告你的 - 对啊，他们都是混球
- They're gonna press charges, you know. - Yeah. They're assholes.
当然了，你偷了他们的东西
Of course they are. You stole from them.
这对我倒是不错
This works out great for me, though.
你妈妈得以保留监护权 我却能把你关进去
Your mother gets to keep custody. I get to take you into custody.
你怎么了？
What is it with you?
现在能偷，就算是条硬汉了？
What, are you a tough guy 'cause you steal now?
拜托，少来点课外辅导了
Please, save me the after-school special.
- 你怎么总要扮成个警察的样子？ - 嘿，这是作你父亲的义务
- Why are you such a cop 24l7? - Hey, it's called being a father.
听我说，你还是当个警察好些
Trust me, you're better at being a cop.
我想该早点回到我妈那儿去了
I just think I should go back to Mom's early.
- 你说什么？ - 怎么，听不见么？
- What did you say? - What, can you not hear me?
我没听见 你再给我说一遍
No, I can't hear you. Say it again.
- 我想该早点回到我妈那儿去了… - 好，你滚啊！
- I think I should go back to Mom's… - Well, then, go!
上帝啊！
Jesus.
嘿，这是丹尼，请留言
Hey, it's Daniel. Leave a message.
是老爸，昨天的事我很抱歉
It's Dad. Sorry about yesterday.
听着，你一直没音讯 能给我回个电话么？
Look, I haven't heard from you. Would you give me a call, please?
丹尼
Daniel.
抱歉，警官 我以为是我儿子打来的
Oh, sorry, Sarge. I thought you were my son.
好，我马上到
Yeah. I'll be right there.
什么情况
What do you got?
县里的石棉清理工正在赶工
County asbestos cleaners were working on a deadline.
他们其中一个发现了这具尸体 就报告给我们了
One of them finds a body, calls it in.
据说这个区域已经被废弃2年了
Says that this whole section's been abandoned for two years.
但是这下面还是有人出没
We've spotted people down here, though.
- 谁？ - 大部分都是无家可归者
- Who? - Well, homeless, mostly.
有小孩说2个月前听到锅炉房有惨叫声
Bunch of kids held a rave in the boiler room about two months back.
- 死亡时间明确了么？ - 法医刚来
- Get an estimate on the time of death? - Forensics just got here.
有警官辨认出死者是你朋友
But it was the arriving officer who called it in as your buddy.
不是，他是我的一个线人
He wasn't my buddy. He was an informant.
只凭看，这位警官就能确认他的身份？
This officer IDed him just by looking at him?
他不是很肯定
Well, he wasn't positive.
- 所以我们才叫你过来 - 好吧
- That's why I wanted you here. - All right.
给我瞧瞧他的脸 2秒钟就能认出来
Well, let me get a look at his face. I'll tell you in two seconds if it's him or not.
问题就在这儿
Therein lies the problem.
没错，是麦克
Yeah, it's Mike.
你打算什么时候告诉我？
When were you gonna tell me about that?
我以为你想亲自看
Thought you'd wanna see it for yourself.
好吧，我看见了
Okay. Well, I saw it.
我承认这样断言有点早，但是…
All right, look. I mean, it's a little early,
到目前为止，一切都和“竖锯”的手法吻合
but so far everything matches Jigsaw's pattern.
我明白，那你叫我干吗？
I can see that. What do you want with me?
现在我们暂时假装没有这方面的经验，好吧？
All right, let's just pretend for a second that this is new to us, all right?
你能想出来谁要对你的人下手么？
Can you think of anyone that would wanna do this to your guy?
凯丽，他是个线人 你想要嫌疑犯名单是吧？
Well, he's an informant, Kerry. You want a list of possible suspects?
找个电话本
Grab a phone book.
小混混们又没有工程学位
Crackhead county punks don't have engineering degrees.
现在，我说让我们从杀人动机来想 把嫌疑人减少
Now, I'd say that our cause of death here narrows that list down just a little bit,
行不行？
wouldn't you?
当然了，你是专家
Sure. And you're the expert.
马修侦探，走近点看
Look closer, Detective Matthews.
看什么？
At what?
你自己去问写了这句话的人吧
Ask whoever wrote it.
你好，麦克
Hello, Michael.
我想和你玩个游戏
I want to play a game.
到目前为止，在你所谓的一生里
So far, in what could loosely be called your life,
你一直通过窥探他人而谋生
you've made a living watching others.
凯丽，你知道你和那家伙有很多相似点
You know, you and that guy have a lot in common, Kerry.
- 哦，是么？ - 没错
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
- 都喜欢耍别人玩 - 什么？
- You both like playing games with people. - Excuse me?
下次在犯罪现场别和我闹着玩了
Don't ever pull some shit like that again on me at a crime scene.
- 听着，不是我要吓你，是他 - 那也不意味着我要上钩
- Look, I'm not the one taunting you. He is. - Doesn't mean I have to take the bait.
- 此外，我手上有一堆案子要办 - 不就是些文书之类的狗屁工作么
- Besides, I got a full caseload as it is. - A bunch of desk errands and shit work.
好了，还有催工的
Yeah, well, between that, IA breathing down my neck,
我那不学好的儿子…
my son's budding criminal career.
和我老婆的离婚律师
and my wife's fucking divorce lawyers,
我说我是忙死了，不是么？
I'd say my hands are pretty full, wouldn't you?
听着，很抱歉
Yeah. Look, I'm sorry.
我希望，或许 这案子我们可以一起办
I was hoping, maybe, that I could bring you in on this one.
凯丽，我们不再是拍档了
We're not partners anymore, Kerry.
就算我们不是拍档，但是…
Hey, forget that we're not partners.
这家伙把你的名字写在墙上了
What about the fact that this guy wrote your fucking name on the wall, huh?
他要找的是你
He asked for you.
有神经病找我也不是第一次了
It's not the first time some psychopath called me out.
好吧，算我求你的怎样？
All right. What about the fact that I'm asking?
爱莫能助
Can't help you.
- Wow。- 你才是“竖锯”案的专家
- Wow. - You're the Jigsaw expert.
你什么时候不想干警察了？
When did you stop being a cop?
马修侦探，走近点看
Look closer, Detective Matthews.
这家伙把你的名字写在墙上了
This guy wrote your fucking name on the wall.
马修侦探，走近点看
Look closer, Detective Matthews.
他要找的是你
He asked for you.
好的，伙计们听着
All right, fellas. Listen up.
这里就是最佳进入点
These are the best entry points.
它们通大马路，有车道和良好的掩护
They're the ones with direct street frontage, vehicle access and good cover.
现在记住… 我们在大白天干
Now, remember, we're doing this in broad daylight.
我可不想惊吓到市民
We don't wanna scare any civilians.
我以前来过，了解地形
Look, I've been there before. I know the location.
直接冲进去 不管是谁在里面
Let's just bust in there and scare the shit out of anyone.
都吓他一跳，明白了？
who happens to be inside, okay?
3人1组进去
We're going in teams of three.
我和阿尔法队一起
I'll go with Team Alpha.
就像过去的好日子，是不？
Just like the good old days, huh?
我以为你很忙的
I thought your caseload was big enough as it is.
我只是随队的
I'm just tagging along for the ride.
快，快，快
Go, go, go, go, go.
盯好后面，注意后面
Check the back. Secure the back.
- 开工 - 上，上
- Go around. - I got it, I got it.
阿尔法队先上 二组，包围这边
Alpha Team, I want you in front. Baker, flank the side.
好，大伙上！
All right, let's do this.
上，上，上
Go, go, go.
前进，前进
Keep moving, keep moving.
不许动！
Freeze!
怎么回事？
What the fuck?
有人受伤！有人受伤！
Officer down! Officer down!
这鬼地方有人监控
The fucking place is wired!
有警官受伤，有警官受伤！
Officer down! Officer down!
妈的，二组，快来
Fuck this! Baker Team, get in here now!
- 快去 - 二组，快来
- All right, go, go! Go! - Baker Team, get in now!
伙计
Guys.
伙计，回答我
Talk to me, guys.
上
Go. Go.
把他抬出去，抬出去
Officer down. Okay.
后援
Stand back.
抬出去
Move him out. Move him out.
无障碍
Clear. Clear.
后援
Stand back.
我们上
Move out!
重复
Repeat.
站住，不许动！
Freeze! Don't move!
把手拿出来 我不会再说第二遍
Let me see your hands. I'm not gonna ask again.
把手放在我能看见的地方
Put your hands where I can see them.
跪下！
Down on your knees!
- 跪下！ - 恐怕我做不到
- Down on your knees! - I'm afraid I can't do that.
把他绑起来
Get him in restraints now.
你有权保持沉默，你有权请律师
You have the right to remain silent. You have the right to an attorney.
如果你付不起… 市政府会给你指定一位
If you can't afford one, one will be appointed to you by the City.
他身上没问题
He's clean.
嘿
Hey.
这足够近了吧？
Is this close enough?
把他弄出来
Get his ass out of here.
事实上，我得呆在这…
Actually, I will need to remain here.
当你忙于处理自己的麻烦的时候 马修侦探
while you deal with your problem, Detective Matthews.
- 什么麻烦？ - 那间房里的麻烦
- What problem? - The problem in that room.
看好他
You keep him secure.
没有可疑
Clear.
糟糕
Shit.
- 怎么了？ - 我不知道
- What? - I don't know.
糟糕
Shit.
我想那是我儿子
I think that's my son.
妈的
Fuck.
他抓住了我儿子
He's got my son.
那他妈的是什么？
What the fuck is that?
嘿，嘿，那他妈的是什么？
Hey! Hey! What the fuck is that?
是你儿子丹尼，你还记得他吧？
It's your son, Daniel. You remember him, don't you?
当然了，你这坨大便渣
I know who he is, you piece of shit.
他怎么会跑到他妈的屏幕上去了
What is he doing on that fucking monitor?
我好久没看那显示器了
Well, I haven't looked at the monitors for some time,
要我说很难
so it would be hard for me to say,
但我可以想象 他肯定害怕得躲在角落里
but I would imagine that he's cowering in a corner.
瞧瞧他的脸…
with a look on his face…
- 你个贱人 - 不，埃里克，等等
- You motherfucker! - No, Eric. Wait.
你个贱人！ 他在哪？
You motherfucker! Where is he? Where is he?
在哪？
Where is he?
他在哪这个问题要你来解决 在一切都太迟了以前
That's a problem you're gonna have to solve before it's too late.
他大约还有2小时
He has about two hours.
此后毒气就会损伤他的神经系统
before the gas creeping into his nervous system.
破坏他的身体组织
begins to break down his body tissue.
他会七窍流血而死
and he begins to bleed from every orifice he has.
哦，没错，会是鲜血淋漓的
Oh, yes. There will be blood.
告诉我他在哪儿
Tell me where he is.
一个安全的地方
He's in a safe place.
- 埃里克 - 我要电话
- Eric. - I need a phone.
- 埃里克，听我说一句 - 把电话给我！
- Eric, just listen to me for a second. - Just give me a phone!
- 听着，这一切都符合他的特点 - 我要确认
- Look, everything about this fits his profile. - I need to be sure.
你打通的是丹尼的电话 他现在不在，你可以…
You've reached Daniel's phone. He's not in right now, but if you'd leave…
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
这里有东西在倒计时
We have something counting down over here.
把排弹组派来
Get me bomb squad, now.
嘿
Hey.
嘿，醒醒
Hey, wake up.
嘿
Hey.
能听见我说话么？
Can you hear me?
她还有气
She's still breathing.
这是什么意思，家庭软禁？
What is this, house arrest?
- 我们在监狱么？ - 不
- Are we in jail? - No.
- 伙计，这不是监狱 - 是么，你蹲了很久监狱么？
- This ain't jail, man. - Oh, yeah? You done a lot of time?
没错，太久了
Yeah. Too much.
- 来人把他妈的门打开 - 我不认为有人在听
- Somebody open the fucking door! - I don't think anybody's listening.
妈的到底是怎么回事？
Damn. What the fuck is this?
有人在监听
Somebody's listening.
没有
No.
这种监视器没有声音的
Those types of cameras don't have sound.
操！
Fuck!
我操！
我怎么会醒来却躺在一个不认识的地方？
How do you just wake up in a room and have no idea where you are?
估计你从来没醉过
I guess you never been drunk before.
我当然醉过了 我上了3年大学呢
I've been drunk. I spent three years at college drunk.
醉…这不是醉酒 这是绑架
This isn't drunk. This is kidnapping.
瞧，我上周在电视里看了一部电影
Look, I saw this movie on TV last week.
有个家伙，是个记者 他要去战区采访
This guy, he was a reporter, and he goes into this war zone, right?
头天晚上他在酒店里睡着了
He goes in to sleep in his hotel room the first night.
嘭！他第二天醒来 却在一个没有窗户也没有灯的监狱里
Bam! He wakes up the next morning, he's in a cell with no windows and no light.
他在那一呆就是9年
And he spent nine years in that room.
9年？ 伙计，那算不了什么，别想了
Nine years? Man, that's nothing. Get over it.
别想了是什么意思？
What do you mean, "get over it"?
我说叫你别闲扯了，找点事做
I mean, stop bitching about it and let's do something.
- 我认为我们都该冷静 - 闭嘴！闭嘴！
- I think we should all just calm down. - Shut up! Shut up!
有声音
I hear something.
是什么？
What is it?
嘀嗒声，我听到嘀嗒声了
It's ticking. I hear ticking.
嘿，嘿，冷静，冷静 你叫什么名字？
Hey, hey, hey. Calm down. Calm down. What's your name?
阿曼达
Amanda.
- 我在哪儿？ - 我不知道
- Where am I? - I don't know.
没人知道，我们都和你一样刚醒
Nobody knows. We all just woke up here like you.
不！
No!
- 不！ - 没事的
- No! - No, it's okay.
不！
No!
- 怎么了？ - 妈的
- What? - Fuck!
怎么了？
What?
你在找什么？
What are you looking for?
这是什么？
What is this?
你需要知道的一切都在这上面
Everything you need to know is on this.
大家好，欢迎
Greetings and welcome.
我相信你们一定想知道这是什么地方
I trust that you are all wondering where you are.
我向你们保证 你们所在的位置并不重要
I can assure you that while your location is not important,
重要的是这几面墙能给你们提供的
what these walls offer for you is important.
如果可以的话，救赎
Salvation, if you earn it.
3个小时后，这座房子的门会打开
Three hours from now, the door to this house will open.
不幸的是，你们只有2小时好活了
Unfortunately, you only have two hours to live.
现在，你们正在呼吸着致命的毒气
Right now, you are breathing in a deadly nerve agent.
从到这儿以后就开始了
You've been breathing it since you arrived here.
熟悉东京地铁毒气事件的人
Those of you familiar with the Tokyo subway attacks.
应该知道它对人体的巨大伤害
will know its devastating effects on the human body.
你们唯一抵抗它并活着走出去的办法
The only way to overcome it and walk out that door.
就是找到解药
is to find an antidote.
它们被藏在房子的各处
Several are hidden around this house.
有一个就在你们面前的保险柜里
One is inside the safe in front of you.
你们都有保险柜的密码
You all possess the combination to the safe.
仔细想想 数字就在你们思想的后面
Think hard. The numbers are in the back of your mind.
怎样排列它们的线索位于彩虹的彼端
The clue to their order can be found over the rainbow.
一旦你们发现了自身的共同点
Once you realize what you all have in common,
你们就会更清楚自己为什么会在这
you will gain a better understanding of why you're here.
「X」标记了线索出现的地方 仔细地找
"X" marks the spot for that clue, so look carefully.
游戏开始！
Let the game begin.
- 这是谁？ - 他说的气体是什么意思？
- Who is this? - What does he mean, gas?
- 你怎么会找这东西的？ - 都是扯谈
- And how did you know where to find this? - This is bullshit.
“不要尝试用这把钥匙打开房门”
"Do not attempt to use this key on the door to this room".
去你妈的
Fuck this, man.
- 没错，去他妈的，这主意不错 - 不，不
- Yeah, fuck this. That's a good idea. - No, no.
- 那不是个好主意 - 那我们怎么办？
- That's not a good idea. - So what are we gonna do, huh?
- 坐在这儿？ - 纸条上说不要用钥匙
- Sit here? - The note said not to use the key.
管它的纸条呢
Who gives a shit about the note, all right?
这就是一个天大的玩笑 而且我要结束它
This is all a fucking big goddamn joke, and I'm about to end it.
你最好现在开口
You better start talking right now.
- 这是什么？ - 一场游戏
- What is this? - It's a game.
这才不是什么他妈的游戏 有人刚被打中了脑袋
It ain't no fucking game! My man just got his head blown off.
- 他在考验我们 - 谁在考验我们？
- He's testing us. - Who's testing us?
“竖锯”
Jigsaw.
- “竖锯”到底是谁？ - 你没看过新闻么？
- Who the hell is Jigsaw? - You don't watch the fucking news?
- 没有，他是谁？ - 一个连环杀手
- No. Who is he? - He's a serial killer.
不，他不是
No, he's not.
他在考验我们 他希望我们能活下去
He's testing us. He wants us to survive this.
但你们要按照规则来
But you have to play by the fucking rules!
我再问你一次，你怎么知道的？
I'm gonna ask you again. How do you know all this?
因为我以前玩过
Because I've played before.
现在叫一个技术支持组过来 查出信号源在哪儿
I want a tech team in here now. Find out where that feed is coming from.
你想要什么？
What do you want with me?
- 你的一点时间，侦探 - 我没时间
- A little of your time, Detective. - I don't have any time.
你问我要什么，我告诉你了
You asked me what I wanted, and I told you.
相信我说的，你儿子麻烦大了
Believe me when I tell you your son is in a lot of trouble.
那我抽出点时间怎样，怎样？
And what if I give you a little bit of my time? What then?
我只想和你谈，其他人都要离开
I only wanna talk to you. Everyone else must leave.
- 这是我的条件 - 不，这是犯罪现场，谁都不能走开
- Those are my conditions. - No. It's a crime scene. Nobody leaves.
他们不需要离开这幢楼
They don't have to leave the building.
只要离开这个区域就好 足够我和你谈了
They just have to leave this area long enough for me to talk to you.
如果你同意，马上就能见到你儿子了
If you agree to that, then you will see your son again.
如果我再也见不到我儿子了，我对天发誓 我会把你的头扭下来
If I don't see my son again, I swear to God I'll rip your fucking head off.
警官，不是我笑你 我是一名癌症患者
I don't intend to mock you, Officer, but I'm a cancer patient.
你又怎么能把我置于 比现在更大的痛苦中呢？
How could you possibly put me in any more pain than I'm already in?
现在把他们叫来
Just get them here now.
好吧，技术组正在赶来
All right, tech team's on the way.
1到2小时就能查出信号来源
Should have your signal traced within an hour, maybe two.
他说要单独和我谈
He said he wants to talk to me alone.
- 可能你是需要和他谈谈 - 去他的
- Well, maybe you should talk to him. - Well, fuck that.
5分钟，老办法搞定他
Five minutes, old-school method.
你知道他对“电话本疗法”没什么反应的
He's not gonna respond to the phone-book treatment. You know that.
别小看一个久经考验的好办法
Don't underestimate a tried and true method here.
我一直跟进这案子
I am the one who has been working on this case from day one.
我只要睁着眼就在想着它
I have been spending every waking moment piecing it together.
可能就因为这个你到现在还没成家
Maybe that's why you ain't got a goddamn family for yourself.
而且也不明白埃里克所受痛苦的原因
and you can't understand what this man is going through.
- 不要 - 瞧…
- Don't. - Look…
我不想和他谈
I don't wanna talk to him.
听着，因为和我扯上关系
Listen, you already lost your son one time before.
你已经失去儿子一次了
because you got involved with me.
这种事不会再发生了
It's not gonna happen again.
放屁！
This is bullshit.
我们怎么办？
What are we gonna do?
迎合他，争取时间
Just humor him. Buy us a little more time.
我们可以赢的，埃里克 我们能击败他
You can win this, Eric. You can beat him.
- 来吧！ - 好吧
- Come on. - All right.
…找到解药
…find an antidote.
它们被藏在房子的各处
Several are hidden around this house.
有一个就在你们面前的保险柜里
One is inside the safe in front of you.
你们都有保险柜的密码
You all possess the combination to the safe.
仔细想想 数字就在你们思想的后面
Think hard. The numbers are in the back of your mind.
怎样排列它们的线索位于…
The clue to their order can be found…
妈的
Shit.
嘿，等一下，你要上哪儿？
Hey, wait a minute. Where you going?
我要找到解药，活着出去
I'm gonna find an antidote, and I'm gonna get out of here.
什么解药？你蹲过大牢
What? Antidote? You been in the joint.
和狱卒聊过
You talked to the guards that run the chambers.
你知道根本没有什么狗屁解药的
You know there ain't no antidote for this shit.
瞧，门没上锁
Look at this. The doors are locked.
听到没有？木头做的
You hear that? It's wood.
而且，伙计，这不是什么碉堡 只是他妈的一个房子
Plaster. It's not a fortress. It's a fucking house.
我要说的就是慢慢来 想出一个策略
All I'm saying is let's just take our time and come up with a game plan.
好吧，你来想策略 行了吧？我自己出去
Well, you come up with the game plan. All right? I'm getting out of here.
看
Look.
- 你还好吧？ - 我没事
- You okay? - Yeah, I'm fine.
如果是你，我不会那么干
I wouldn't do that if I was you.
你不知道那门后面是什么
You don't know what's behind that fucking door.
我操
Fuck.
糟糕
Shit.
撤
Clear the room.
好了，我们来谈啊
Okay. Let's talk.
坐下，埃里克
Sit down, Eric.
我想做个游戏
I want to play a game.
规则很简单
The rules are simple.
你要做的就是坐在这里和我说话
All you have to do is sit here and talk to me,
听我说话
listen to me.
如果时间到了… 你会发现你儿子
If you do that long enough, then you will find your son.
在一个安全的地方
in a safe and secure state.
我们还没正式介绍呢 我叫约翰
We haven't been properly introduced. My name's John.
- 我以为你喜欢被称为“竖锯” - 不
- I thought you liked to be called Jigsaw. - No, no.
是警察和媒体起了“竖锯”这个别名
It was the police and the press who coined the nickname Jigsaw.
我从不那样自称
I never encouraged or claimed that.
我从实验对象身上砍下来的锯渣
The jigsaw piece I cut from my subjects was only ever meant to be a symbol.
只是作为一个象征
that that subject was missing something.
象征他缺少了一项谜样的人类重要组成部分 生存本能
A vital piece of the human puzzle. The survival instinct.
这真的很有趣，约翰
This is all really, really interesting, John,
但现在我非常希望你能和我谈谈…
but right now I'd really like for you to talk to me…
我正在和你谈啊
I am talking to you.
你没有在听
You're not listening.
- 别忘了规则 - 我在听
- Don't forget the rules. - I'm listening to you,
但我现在耳朵里充斥的却是一些
but all I'm hearing is the same sick fucking bullshit.
每次我调查你们这些变态狂2秒钟之内
that comes about two seconds into every interview I've ever done.
就能听到的胡言乱语
with one of you fucking people.
你采用的真是个不错的侦破手法
Well, that's an interesting approach to police work, isn't it?
你不是应该装成我的朋友
Aren't you supposed to be convincing me that I'm your friend,
给我一种错误的安全感 来骗取我的信任么？
lulling me into a false sense of security so that I'll confide in you?
现在要我按手册办事很难 因为我儿子在你手上，约翰
It's a little hard to follow the manual when you've got my son, John.
手册？
The manual?
你现在想对我做什么？
What do you really wanna do to me right now, huh?
你5年前做了些什么？
What would you have done five years ago, huh?
你当时按照手册办事了么？
Would you have followed the manual then?
你不是要用手电把我下巴打下来么？
Would you have broken my jaw with a flashlight?
你好像很了解我
You seem to know a whole lot about me.
我知道你以前被认为是一名无畏的警官
I know you were once considered a fearless police officer.
你现在坐对面是不是感觉安全多了？
Do you feel a whole lot safer now that you only sit behind a desk?
我现在感慨万千
I feel a whole lot of things right now.
但你知道自己还活着，就是这种感觉
But you feel alive. That's what you feel.
才是关键
And that's the point.
你能不能
Would you.
好心地帮我拿杯水过来？
kindly get me a glass of water?
非常感谢
I would very much appreciate that.
妈的
Fuck!
现在我们明白蛮干
Well, we've established.
是打不开那扇门的
that the macho-bullshit approach isn't opening the door.
- 有什么好主意么？ - 看看是谁在说话
- Any other suggestions? - Look who's talking.
你唯一会开的门就是你双腿中间的那扇
The only door you know how to open is between your legs.
- 你他妈的给我闭嘴，好吗？ - 别这样，伙计
- Why don't you shut the hell up, all right? - Come on, man.
- 你给我闭嘴 - 我听够了你的废话
- Why don't you shut the hell up? - I'm sick of your bullshit.
- 好了，退后，贱人 - 你个阳痿
- That's right, back up, bitch! - You little dickhead.
- 混球！ - 喂！
- Asshole! - Hey!
你们想干嘛？ 好了，够了，退后
What you gonna do? Yeah, yeah, that's right, back up!
好，不要窝里斗
Okay, man. All right. Nobody take shit from nobody.
我们说好了的
We've established that.
- 有发现么？ - 没，没有
- Did you find anything? - No. Nothing.
你手臂上的印记… 是在朱丽叶监狱服刑的标志吧？
So, that ink on your arm, that's Joliet, right?
是啊，怎么了？
Yeah. So?
- 我也在那儿蹲过 - 很骄傲么
- Well, I did a stretch there myself. - I'm proud of you.
你呢，是在哪儿改造的？
And you, what is your correctional facility of choice?
你的意思是？
What's your point?
我的意思是你那一套 不是从研究生院学来的吧
My point is, you didn't get that way by teaching grade school, right?
这样我们就有3个人曾经进过监狱
That makes three of us that's done time.
我认为我们应该集中考虑那卷磁带
I think we should be concentrating on that tape,
因为上面说我们有很多 不为人知的共同点
'cause that tape said we have more in common than we know.
我说我们3个进过监狱的…
I say the three of us doing stretches…
嘿！这儿有扇门
Hey! I found a door over here.
给我手电
I need the flashlight.
那边
Over there.
什么东西？
What the fuck?
哦，糟糕
Oh, shit!
嘿
Hey!
- 该死，小子 - 抱歉
- Damn, kid. - Sorry.
- “欧比” - 欧比是他妈的什么？
- "Obi". - What the fuck is a Obi?
欧比，是我的名字
Obi. It's my name.
你好，欧比 我想和你玩个游戏
Hello, Obi. I want to play a game.
多年来，你一直
For years, you have burned those around you.
欺骗自己周围的人
with your lies, cons and deceits.
现在你有机会赎回
Now you'll have a chance to redeem yourself.
你玩弄他人的罪行
for the games you've played with others.
通过参加我的这个游戏
by playing one of mine.
在你面前的仪器里有2剂解药
Inside the device in front of you are two antidotes.
可以解除你们体内的毒素
for the poison coursing through your veins.
其中1个是作为我谢谢你 帮我绑架其他人的礼物
One is my gift to you for helping me kidnap the others.
另1个需要你送给他人
The second is yours to donate.
但是，要拿到它们中的1个是要付出代价的
However, one of them will come with a price.
记住，欧比
Remember, Obi,
一旦你身处地域 能救出你的便只有魔鬼
once you are in hell, only the devil can help you out.
等一下 “绑架其他人”是什么意思？
Wait a minute. What does that mean, "kidnap the others"?
- 我怎么知道？ - 因为是你把我们抓进来的
- How would I know? - Because you put us here.
汽车里的人
The car.
是…
It was…
我就知道我见过他
I knew I knew him.
你是我在这醒来前见到的最后1个人
You're the last person I saw before I woke up here.
是你干的
You did this.
你肯定是他么？你最好搞清楚点
Are you sure it's him? You better be sure.
我肯定
I'm sure.
要是我你也会这么做的 我是被逼的
You would have done the same. I did what I had to do.
我给你个机会
I'll give you a choice.
- 你现在有5秒钟告诉我们怎么出去 - 我不知道出去的路
- You got five seconds to get us out of here. - I don't know the way out.
胡说！你把我们关进来的 也就能把我们弄出去
Bullshit! You put us in here. You can get us out of here.
不，我不行
No, I can't.
- 那你死定了 - 你也是
- Then you're a dead man. - So are you.
不行，等等，等等 等等，听我说
He's not gonna… Wait, wait, wait, wait! Wait, listen to me.
在炉子后面有2管解药
Okay, we got two antidotes at the back of that oven.
- 我们在浪费时间 - 浪费时间？你开玩笑吗？
- We're wasting time here. - Wasting time? Are you kidding me?
是他在半夜里绑架了我
He kidnapped me in the middle of the night.
我们不知道管道里有什么陷阱
We don't even know what's in those syringes.
你愿意伸手进去试试么？
You willing to stick yourself in the arm to find out?
是啊，好的，等一下
Okay, wait. So who gets them?
我说，哪2个人可以用它们来解毒呢？
I mean, there's two. So which two people get the antidote?
这个等会再说
We'll work that out later!
现在，你要么进去
Right now you're going in there.
要么我就地把你宰了
or I'll kill you where you stand.
糟糕
Shit.
你要想拿刀子来要挟我 最好还是动点真格的
If you're gonna threaten me with a knife, you may as well cut me a little.
我会去拿那些解药的
I guess I'm going in there to get those needles.
但我要用掉其中的一个
But I get one.
- 我的一份 - 快点
- One for me. - Hurry up.
下来，宝贝 你们可以抢这一只了
Come on, baby. You guys can fight over this one.
谢谢，欧比
Thank you, Obi.
拿到了
Come on.
- 哦，糟糕，他妈的门关上了 - 开门！
- Oh, shit. The fucking door closed! - Open the door!
开门！
Open the door!
锁上了，我打不开
It's locked. I can't open it.
开门！
Open the door!
打开这该死的门！这可不好玩
Open the fucking door! Not funny!
快，把他弄出来
Come on! Get him out of there!
门
The door!
被钉上了
The nail!
我打不开
I can't get it open!
- 把他救出来 - 这可不好玩
- Get him out of there! - Not funny!
用外套 用你他妈的外套
Use your coat! Use your fucking coat!
- 快，他快烧死了 - 不要！
- Come on! He's burning up! - Stop it!
- 快 - 转过来
- Come on! - Turn! Turn!
不要！
Stop it.
- 用力啊 - 不要！
- You gotta put your weight on it. - Stop it.
他快要死了！
My man's dying!
伙计们，那边有扇窗
Guys, there's a window over here.
- 他拿到解药了 - 不要！
- He's got the antidote. - Stop it!
把他弄出来
Get him out.
- 快！ - 打开它！
- Hurry! - Get it open.
- 操！- …是玻璃的
- Fuck! - …glass or something.
- 不要！ - 坚持，伙计，我们会把你救出来的
- Stop it! - Hang on, man. We're gonna get you out.
靠
Shit.
不要，不要了！
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
闪开！快他妈的闪开！
Get out of the fucking way! Go on, move! Move!
糟了！快点
Here. Shit! Come on!
针管呢？
The needles!
他拿到针管了 他妈的本来在那的呀
He ain't got the fucking needles! It's fucking in there!
我要他妈的针管 我要他妈的针管
I want the fucking needles! I want the fucking needles!
冷静
Calm down.
- 妈的 - 针管都化了
- Fuck! - The needles are fucking melted.
没了
They're gone.
他自找的
He had a choice.
凯丽，又死了1个
Another one down, Kerry.
我们还要在这混蛋身上浪费多少时间？
How much more time are we gonna waste on this bastard?
这不是浪费时间
We're not wasting time.
我们在做我们该做的
We're doing exactly what we should be doing until the tech team gets here.
在我看来不是
It's not what it looks like to me.
你看，侦探，达尔文的进化论
You see, Detective, Darwin's theory of evolution.
和适者生存那一套 是从他访问加拉帕戈斯那次旅行中得来的
and survival of the fittest, based on his little trip to the Gal醦agos,
对这个星球已经不再适用了
no longer applies on this planet.
人类已经没有优势
We have a human race that doesn't have the edge.
和意愿生存下去
or the will to survive.
- 你他妈的想要什么？ - 现在想保持冷静很难，不是么？
- What the fuck do you want? - It's hard to remain calm, isn't it,
当你儿子在那些屏幕里走来走去的时候
when your son is walking around on those monitors?
我不能满足你的需要 除非你告诉我到底想要什么
I can't give you what you want if you don't tell me what the fuck it is.
我告诉过你了
I told you what it is.
- 记住规则就好了 - 不，你说你想谈谈
- Just remember the rules. - No, you said you wanted to talk.
然后你又说想做个游戏 你在说，但全是些废话
Then you said you wanted to play a game. You're talking, but it means nothing!
埃里克，你说什么东西能治好癌症？
What do you think the cure for cancer is, Eric?
- 什么？ - 癌症的解药
- What? - The cure for cancer.
- 是什么？ - 我不知道
- What is it? - I don't know what it is,
但我知道肯定不是
but I know it's not killing and torturing people.
为了自己变态的快感而虐杀别人 都是他们自己选的
for your own sick fucking pleasure.
我的一生中从未谋杀过任何人
I've never murdered anyone in my life. The decisions are up to them.
好吧，用枪指着别人的脑袋
Yeah, well, putting a gun to someone's head.
逼着他们自己扣下扳机也该算作谋杀
and forcing them to pull the trigger is still murder.
曾几何时，暴力成为你的问题了？
Since when is force a problem for you?
你为什么这么想要回你的儿子？
Why are you so desperate to get your son back?
因为他是我儿子
'Cause he's my son.
你离开他之前说过的最后一句话是什么？
What's the last thing you said to him before you left him?
好，你滚吧！
Well, then, go!
在我看来儿子垂死挣扎的事实
Seems to me that the knowledge of your son's impending death is causing you to act.
触动到你了
Forgive all his sins, to wipe the slate clean…
为什么只有在性命攸关的时候 我们才想起这么做？
Why is it that we're only willing to do that when a life is at stake?
我一直爱儿子，这从来没变过
I've always loved my son. That's never changed.
不，不，现在变了
No, no. It's changed now.
我说，得知死讯能改变一切
You see, the knowledge of death changes everything.
如果我告诉你死亡的具体时间
If I were to tell you the exact date and time of your own death,
那会彻底颠覆你的世界
it would shatter your world completely.
我知道这感觉
I know.
你能想象到么？ 有人叫你坐下来…
Can you imagine what it feels like to have someone sit you down…
约翰·克莱姆？
John Kramer.
…然后告诉你死期将至
…and tell you that you're dying?
那种悲痛？
The gravity of that?
钟滴滴答答地走着
That the clock's ticking for you.
就在那一秒，你的世界就象裂开了个大缝
In a split second, your world is cracked open.
你看问题，感觉事情的角度都变了
You look at things differently. You smell things differently.
你珍惜一切，不管是一杯水 还是一次公园里的散步
You savor everything, be it a glass of water or a walk in the park.
约翰，时间在流逝
The clock is ticking, John.
但大多数人都很幸运
But most people have the luxury.
他们不知道钟什么时候会停
of not knowing when that clock's gonna go off,
讽刺的是，因为这个
and the irony of it is that that keeps them from really living their life.
他们不能好好地活
It keeps them sleepwalking.
他们喝水 却从来不感受它的甘甜
It keeps them drinking that glass of water, but never really tasting it.
约翰，你还能救他们
You can still fix this, John.
我们能救的了你么？
Yeah, but can we fix you?
我？
Me?
我没救了
I'm not fixable.
我得了癌症
I've got cancer.
你把癌症当成犯罪的借口
You're using cancer as an excuse for what you do?
不
No.
不是癌症让我走上这条路的
The cancer isn't what started me in my work.
我打算结束自己生命的那一刻
It was the moment I decided to end my life.
才是我行动的开始
that started me in my work.
而且使我的生命有了意义
and brought meaning to it.
我操！
Fuck!
我曾经想自杀
I had literally driven myself to suicide,
但失败了
and I had failed.
我的身体抵挡不住癌细胞的攻击
My body had not been strong enough to repel cancer cells,
但我却大难不死
yet I had lived through a plunge off a cliff.
奇迹般的，我活下来了
But, to my amazement, I was alive.
于是我决心把剩余的时间
And I was determined to spend the rest of my days.
花在研究人类本性上面
testing the fabric of human nature.
你明白么，埃里克？
Do you understand, Eric?
约翰，乘你现在还有机会 做点什么吧
You got a chance to do something. Do it right now, John.
告诉我儿子的下落
Just tell me where my son is.
我会帮你
I'll help you.
我不要你帮… 而且我知道你现在还不懂
I don't need your help, and I can tell you still don't understand.
不珍惜生命的人，不配拥有它
Those who don't appreciate life do not deserve life.
我儿子珍惜自己的命
My son appreciates his life.
那你珍惜自己的么？ 你珍惜你儿子的么？
But do you appreciate yours? Do you appreciate your son's?
哦，你到底在胡扯什么？
Oh, this is shit!
别忘了规则
Don't forget the rules.
如果你想找到儿子的话
if you wanna find your son.
你们在哪？
Where are you?
不，不，我们没有15分钟
No. No, we don't have 15 minutes.
我们需要信号源的位置
We need that location to the video feed.
嘿，我不认为该放弃
Hey. I don't think we should stop, okay?
喂，能听见我说话么？
Laura, can you hear me?
我在这鬼地方已经是第2次醒来了
That's the second time I've had to wake up in this shithole.
你还能站起来么？
Think you can stand up?
可以，但我不想
Yeah, but I don't really want to.
还有那么多事没做
There's so much left to do.
那么多人没说过话
So many people left to talk to.
我不会就这样死了吧
This can't be it.
不会的
It's not.
- 阿曼达，你说你成功脱险过？ - 我什么？
- Amanda, you said you survived this, right? - I what?
这家伙，不管他是谁
This guy, whoever's doing it,
你说你和他玩过 而且活下来了
you said that you've played before and you survived.
没错
Yeah.
那意味着我们也能活下去
So that means we could survive.
没错
Yeah.
阿曼达，他为什么选你？
Wait. Amanda, why did he pick you?
因为我吸毒上瘾
Because I was a fucking junkie.
有趣的是… 我通过了他的考验
And the funny thing is, I passed his little test.
如果你已经通过了，那怎么现在又回来了？
If you passed his test, then why are you back here?
我虐待自己
I wasn't being very good to myself.
- 你什么时候开始吸毒的？ - 从监狱里开始的
- How long have you… - I started in jail.
- 你为什么被抓？ - 藏毒
- What were you arrested for? - Possession.
但是我以为你…
But I thought you said that…
可能你该去问问逮捕我的警察
Maybe you should talk to the cop who arrested me.
我想你从没被逮捕过吧
I'm guessing you've never been arrested before.
没有
No.
嗯，我的意思是 我也惹过不少麻烦，三分钟热度
I mean, I've been in trouble a few times, you know, in and out of stuff.
我的爸爸…
My dad's a…
他可真不是好惹的
He's a real hardass.
他现在可能派全城半数的人在找我…
You know, he's probably got half the city right now looking for me.
然后因为我的失踪而海扁我一顿
just so he can kick my ass for disappearing on him.
对
Yeah.
可能吧
Probably.
我们发现了一扇门，过来
We found a door. Come on.
快点，我们得走了
Come on. We have to go.
这是唯一一扇没上锁的 但我们打不开
It's the only one without a lock, but we can't get it open.
- 怎么了？ - 卡住了
- How's it going? - It's stuck on something.
哦，糟糕
Oh, shit.
- 来，让我试试，让开，让开 - 你放松点好吗？老天！
- Here, let me try. Move, move! Come on. - Will you take it easy? Jesus!
别吵了，好吗
Just back up, all right?
如果打不开，肯定是个陷阱
If it's stuck, it's a trap.
女士，整个屋子就是个大陷阱
Lady, this whole house is a trap.
显然，有些人不想我们进这间屋子
Obviously someone didn't want us to get into this room.
- 现在怎么办？ - 我马上就回来，好么？
- Now what? - I'm gonna be right back, okay?
不管是什么，我们3分钟之内都要完成
Whatever we do, we got four minutes to get it done.
你好，泽维 我想和你做个游戏
Hello, Xavier. I want to play a game.
这个游戏…
The game I want to play is very similar.
和你作为毒贩子玩的那个非常相似
to the one that you've been playing as a drug dealer.
一个把希望卖给绝望中的人的游戏
The game of offering hope to the desperate for a price.
我想我们都同意你现在的处境很绝望
I think we can agree that your situation is desperate.
所以我把希望卖给你
So I offer you hope.
我的条件就是 要你进入你逼顾客们…
The price you pay is that you must crawl into the same pit of squalor.
进入的肮脏的陷阱里
you force your customers into.
- 在你们进来时… - 我的天呐
- By entering this room… - Oh, my God.
…计时器便已启动
…a timer has been started.
到时以后 你们面前的那扇门就会永远被锁上
When the timer expires, the door in front of you will be locked forever.
- …在那以前 - 各位？各位
- Only in finding the key… - Guys? Guys.
- 怎么了？ - 看
- What? - Look.
你们能不能把它打开…
Before the timer runs out can you unlock it…
- 并拿出里面的解药？ - 老天爷啊
- and retrieve the antidote inside. - Oh, my God.
关于钥匙的位置我只给你们一个提示…
I will give you just one hint as to where that key is.
大海捞针
It will be like finding a needle in a haystack.
游戏开始
Let the game begin.
得有人下去
Somebody's going in there.
瞧瞧，现在得有人下去
Now, look, somebody's fucking going in there, man.
不！不！不！
No! No! No!
- 我靠 - 你要干吗？
- Oh, shit. - What the fuck are you doing?
- 住手！ - 你要干吗？
- Stop. - What are you doing?
- 不！不！ - 你他妈的在干什么！
- No! No! - What the fuck are you doing?
- 不！不要！求你了 - 放她走
- No! No! Please! - Let her go now.
不！
No!
我靠
Shit!
我的天
My God.
快点！
Come on!
- 我们没时间了 - 我靠
- We don't have time! - Oh, shit.
你他妈犯什么病了？
What the fuck's wrong with you?
你搞什么？
What are you doing?
- 你他妈的疯了 - 快点
- You're out of your fucking mind. - Hurry up.
哦，糟糕
Oh, shit!
快点
Come on!
没时间了
We don't have time.
快他妈找啊
Keep fucking looking.
- 快点，快点 - 去你妈的
- Come on! Come on! - Fuck you!
我操
What the fuck?
来人帮帮她
Somebody's gotta help her.
怎么了，大伙？
What the fuck, guys?
操！
Fuck!
不！不！不！
No. No. No. No.
不！
No!
不，不！
No. No!
快
Come on.
不，不，不
No, no, no.
- 你这婊子！ - 好了，够了
- You fucking bitch! - All right. That's enough.
我和你没完
That's not nearly enough, man.
少废话了
Stop this bullshit.
你没听见那带子么？
Did you hear that tape?
他知道我们我们的…名字
He knows about us. Our names.
我们一定是漏掉了什么
There's something that we're not seeing.
监狱
Jail.
你说你们3个蹲过
You said you three had been there.
应该是4个
Make it four.
- 怎么进去的？ - 无关紧要
- For what? - Doesn't matter.
还有什么人要坦白么？
Anybody else wanna own up?
你呢？是不是进过少管所？
What about you? You got juvie written all over you.
没有
No, never been.
好吧
All right.
- 我们谈谈 - 不
- Let's talk this out. - No.
到此为止
No more talking.
你们唯一的共同点就是 拖我的后腿
The only thing you people have in common is holding me back.
我要走了
I'm gone.
- 技术组跑哪儿去了？ - 就快到了
- Where is this goddamn tech team? - They'll be here any second.
我听不下去了
I'm not listening to this anymore.
- 简直是度日如年 - 听着，我了解这家伙的手法
- Another second is too fucking long. - Look, I know how this guy works, okay?
他在玩游戏
He's playing a game.
埃里克只要多坚持一会就好了
Eric just needs to stay in it a little bit longer.
看看时间
Take a look at the clock.
你该用点发散思维了 否则他儿子肯定要挂了
You need to start thinking outside the box, or his son is gonna end up in one.
他的杰作
His work.
想了解他，应该从这里开始
You wanna get to him, that's how you do it.
他在享受这一刻
I mean, he's relishing this.
此刻他才能被倾听，被学习
It's an opportunity to be heard, to be studied.
通过破坏他的作品来威胁他
Threaten to destroy his work.
埃里克，没这些证据你怎么定我的罪啊？
How will you get your conviction without all this evidence, Eric?
不要它们也能治得了你
I don't need this shit to convict you.
随便你，毁了它们吧
So go ahead. Destroy it.
- 我会的 - 全毁了吧
- I will. - Destroy it all.
你知道这救不了儿子
Just know it will not save your son if you do.
你杀了我儿子，我就杀了你
You kill my son, I kill you.
尽管来啊
Go ahead.
你在等什么？ 我们都清楚你是什么人，长官
Why wait? We both know the sort of person you are, sir.
- 闪开 - 你可以开枪打伤
- Get out of here. - The sort of person.
手无寸铁的囚犯
who guns down an unarmed suspect.
而且，为了定罪
In fact, the sort of person who plants evidence.
不惜假造证据
in order to obtain a conviction.
你这种人老婆嫌，儿子厌
The sort of person whose wife leaves him and whose son hates him.
闭上你的鸟嘴！
Shut the fuck up!
- 他配制好了卫星定位 - 快走
- Okay, set up all the traces to the satellite. - Let's go.
技术组到了
Your tech team's arrived.
刚好来得及
Just in time.
你最好希望他们能找到信号源
You better hope they find the source of that feed.
埃里克，有些事我还没告诉你
There's something I haven't told you, Eric.
我不想听你废话了
I'm done listening to you.
那或许我可以拿给你看
Maybe I can just show it to you.
不幸的是，要我拿不太现实
But, unfortunately, it's going to be difficult for me to get it myself,
或许你可以让对讲机那头的同事
so perhaps you could ask the people who are listening on that walkie in there.
拿给我，好么？
if they could get it for me, all right?
棕色的桌子
Brown desk.
下面第2个抽屉
Second drawer down.
你可能不记得那些人了
You may not remember all those people,
但我肯定他们还没忘了你
but I'm sure they remember you.
你逮捕了他们
You were the arresting officer in all of their cases,
而且假造了证据
and you were the one who planted all the evidence.
定了他们的罪
used to obtain their convictions.
是你把他们关进去的
You were the one who put them away.
你儿子正在和一群
Your son is playing a game.
不太喜欢你的人一起做游戏呢 侦探先生
with a lot of people who don't like you very much, Detective.
他们要是发现了他的身份可就糟了
It would be a shame if they discovered who he was.
你们都有保险柜的密码
You all possess the combination to the safe.
仔细想想 数字就在你们思想的后面
Think hard. The numbers are in the back of your mind.
怎样排列它们的线索位于彩虹的彼端
The clue to their order can be found over the rainbow.
狗日的
Son of a bitch.
- 你在干嘛？ - 我还没想好
- What are you doing? - I haven't decided yet.
你知道，其他人… 他们怕你
You know, the others, they're scared of you.
不错
Good.
你和我…
You and me,
我们可以继续争斗下去
we can keep going at each other like we're back in the yard,
或者齐心协力抓住凶手
or we can come together and figure out who's doing this to us.
你们想干嘛就干嘛吧
You and the others can do what you want.
我已经找到了想要的东西
I already found what I'm looking for.
你让我想起了自己
You remind me of me.
不管是什么处境
No matter what kind of fucked-up situation you're in,
你总能设法找到一个敌人
you always gotta find yourself an enemy.
你明白么？ 兄弟，我有敌人
You know what? I got enemies, man.
在这些他妈的墙的外面
Outside these fucking walls, bro.
他们在找我
And they're looking for me.
如果找不到… 他们就会对我亲近的人下手
And if they don't find me, they're going after the ones closest to me.
我的家人
My family.
你明白么？
You understand?
不
No.
我不明白
I don't understand.
这就是我，我就喜欢这样
It's just me, and that's the way I like it.
现在，转过身去
Now, turn around.
- 什么？ - 转身
- What? - Turn around.
哦，糟糕
Oh, shit.
- 不，我们不能停下来 - 糟糕
- No. We can't stop. - Shit.
哦，上帝
Oh, my God.
我们已经在这2小时了 如果那带子里说的没错…
We've been here for two hours. If what that tape says is true,
前门会在1小时内打开
then in one hour, the front door will open.
我们坚持不了那么久
We're not gonna make it that long.
你这态度还真不错啊
That's a real winning attitude.
她说的不错
She knows what she's talking about.
哦，是么？
Oh, yeah?
「X」是标记点
"X" marks the spot.
什么？
What?
「X」标记…
"X" marks…
标记了地点
Marks the spot.
标记了答案
There's the answer.
你和他一起干什么？
What are you doing with him?
他是你父亲？
This is your father?
- 怎么，你认识他？ - 没错
- What? You know him? - Yeah.
是他把我抓起来的 他设的局
He's the guy who put me away. He set me up.
告诉我他不是你爸爸
Tell me that's not your father.
没事的，没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
我现在谁都不信了
I can't trust any of you.
你们俩靠自己吧
You two are on your own.
现在我们知道自己的共同点了
Now we know what we have in common.
阿曼达，求你了，我不知道
Amanda, please. I didn't know.
嘿，小鬼，阿曼达
Hey, kid! Amanda!
你们上哪儿去了？
Where are you?
求你别丢下我
Please don't leave me.
我们该走了
We gotta move.
喂，小鬼
Hey, kid!
阿曼达
Amanda!
我发现出路了
I found a way out.
八
Eight.
嘿，小鬼
Hey, kid!
不…要…跑
Do not run.
埃里克，埃里克！
Eric. Eric.
不，住手！
No! Stop!
把手拿开
Get off of me!
我们试过你的方法了
We tried it your way.
人渣，我儿子在哪？
You motherfucker! Where is he?
埃里克
Eric.
该死
Damn it.
你只能眼睁睁看儿子流血了
I'd like to go now until your son is pissing blood.
现在，才是得奖的埃里克·马修
Now, that's the Eric Matthews they gave medals to.
救命！
Help!
救救我！
Help me!
哦，老天
Oh, my God.
乔纳斯
Jonas.
救命！救命！
Help me! Help me!
救命！
Help!
拜托
Please.
没事的
It's okay.
- 救命！ - 没事的
- Help me. - It's okay.
不！不！
No. No.
不！
No!
妈的！
Fucker!
不！
No!
阿曼达
Amanda.
人渣，没人在听了
Nobody's listening anymore, asshole.
张嘴，张嘴！ 快点
Open your mouth. Open your mouth! Come on.
就这样
There you go.
你现在想告诉我他的位置了？
You gonna tell me where he is now, huh?
什么？
What?
再说一次
Say it again.
游戏结束
Game over.
我现在就带你到房子去
I'll take you to the house.
你现在就得带我去 马上
You're gonna take me right now. Right now.
我只会带你
I will only take you.
其他人不行
No one else.
好吧，我和你
All right. Just me and you.
- 我们怎么出去？ - 墙上有个按钮
- How do we get out of here? - There's a button on the wall.
你最好快点
You'd better hurry.
时间不多了
There's not much time left.
- 电梯！ - 快
- The elevator! - Come on!
操！
Fuck!
立即封锁仓库！
Secure the warehouse now!
- 现在出发，走！走！ - 该死
- All right, let's go! Go! Go, go, go! - Damn it.
有发现了
We've got a lock.
这是凯丽，他们俩都不见了
This is Kerry. They're both gone.
如果找不到儿子，我发誓…
If I don't find my son, I swear to God…
凯丽，他们不见了
Kerry, they're gone.
他妈的不见了
Fucking gone.
好，凯丽，我们发现房子的位置了
Yes! Kerry. We got a lock. We got a lock on the house.
- 里格，找到了 - 什么？
- Rigg, we got it. - What?
北海德月街237号
237 North Hyde Crescent.
- 是北海德月街 - 北海德月街237号，收到
- That's North Hyde Crescent. - 237 North Hyde Crescent. Got it.
现在上哪儿？
Where to now?
一直向前
Straight ahead.
快点，快点 你们在哪儿？
Come on, come on. Where are you?
阿弗雷德街右转
Make a right on Alfred.
开门！
Open the fucking door!
Open the door!
你们哪儿也去不了了
There's nowhere to go.
我要的只是你们脑门后面的号码
All I want is the number on the back of your head.
你们无路可逃了，阿曼达
There's nowhere to go! Come on, Amanda!
我支持不住了
I can't hold it.
快，让我进去
Come on! Let me in!
让我进去！
Let me in!
开门，快点啊
Open the door! Come on!
我们怎么办？
What do we do?
下条街左转
Take a left at the next street.
左手边最后1幢就是
It's the last house on the left.
哦，糟糕
Oh, shit.
糟糕
Shit!
快点！
Come on!
快点，阿曼达
Come on, Amanda!
- 那是什么？ - 一扇门
- Amanda, what is it? - It's a door.
一扇他妈的门
It's a fucking door.
你们无路可逃了，无路可逃了！
You have nowhere to go! You have nowhere to go!
快！
Come on!
帮我把这个挪开
Help me move this thing.
我不会伤害你们的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
快点，阿曼达
Come on, Amanda!
靠，锁上了
Shit, it's locked!
让我进去
Let me in!
快开门啊
Come on, open the door!
快点！
Come on!
钥匙 和录音机一起的那个
The key. The one we found with the tape recorder.
在哪？在哪？
Where is it? Where is it?
妈的
Fuck!
乔纳斯，最后在乔纳斯手上
Jonas. Jonas had it last.
- 快点，阿曼达 - 赶快找
- Come on, Amanda! - Find it! Hurry!
快点
Come on!
快开门！
Come on, open the door!
让我进去！
Let me in!
埃里克，进屋之后 你会用到这把钥匙
Eric, you're gonna need this key when you get inside the house.
我们这是在哪？
Where the hell are we?
跑，快跑
Run! Run!
丹尼？
Daniel?
丹尼！
Daniel!
丹尼，我们得走了！
Daniel, we gotta go!
- 我们得走了！快点！ - 跑
- We gotta go! Come on! - Run.
好，快点 快走，快走，快走
All right, come on. Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
快走，快走，快走！
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
冲！
Go, go, go!
- 走廊没人 - 我们进来了
- Hallway's clear. - We're in.
丹尼！
Daniel!
- 包围1楼了 - 进去，进去
- The ground floor is secure. - Moving up. Moving up.
凯丽，我们在房子里了 重复，我们在房子里了
Kerry, we're in the house. I repeat, we're in the house.
警官，我没看见你 重复，我没看见你
Cannot see you, Sergeant. Repeat, cannot see you.
重复，我没看见你
Repeat. I cannot see you.
- 大伙们都在哪 - 你发现什么了
- Where the hell is everybody? - What is your 20?
里格，听到了么？
Rigg, do you copy?
你好，辛德先生
Hello, Mr. Hindle.
跟随你的心
Follow your heart.
我们早该看看那里的
I really wish I had checked in there first.
这他妈的是什么？
What the fuck is this?
我的名字是他妈的大糊涂 你叫什么？
My name is very fucking confused. What's your name?
我现在要杀了你老公
I'm gonna kill your husband now, Mrs. Gordon.
他不想让我们锯断脚镣
He doesn't want us to cut through our chains.
你在干吗？不！
What are you doing to me? No!
他想让我们锯的是腿
He wants us to cut through our feet.
不！哦，上帝
No! Oh, my God!
好痛！
It hurts!
不！
No!
丹尼！
Daniel!
丹尼，别，别留下我
Daniel, no. Don't leave me.
求你了
Please.
他死了
He's gone.
没关系
Doesn't matter.
我要的只是他脖子后面的号码
All I want is the number on the back of his neck.
还有你的
And then yours.
那你还不知道自己的号码呢
You still don't know your own number.
如果我不告诉你，你怎么办？
How are you gonna get it if I don't tell you?
丹尼！
Daniel!
我靠
Shit.
快跑！
Run!
操
Fuck.
丹尼？
Daniel?
警官，我还是没看见你
I still cannot see you, Sergeant.
里格，收到么？
Rigg, do you copy?
- 左侧安全 - 右侧安全
- Left side clear. - Right side clear.
全部安全
All clear.
警官，我没看见你 重复，我没看见你
I still can't see you, Sergeant. I repeat, cannot see you.
是录播的
It's not live.
凯丽，我们来错了地方
Kerry, we're in the wrong fucking house!
他们早就死了
They've been dead this whole fucking time.
- 带队出来 - 走
- Get your team out of there. - Let's go.
丹尼？
Daniel?
丹尼
Daniel.
你好，埃里克 你可能不记得我了…
Hello, Eric. You probably don't even remember me,
但你曾经改变过我的生活
but you changed my life once.
你把我送进了监狱
You sent me to prison.
我做错了很多事…
I was guilty of a lot of things,
但绝没犯过你陷害我的藏毒罪
but not the drug charge you framed me for.
当你被抓起来 就不知道自己失去了什么
You wouldn't know the things you lose when you're locked away.
第二次有人改变我的生活的时候 我有罪
The second time somebody changed my life, I was guilty.
你好， 阿曼达
Hello, Amanda.
但那天我的生命得到了救赎
But my life was saved that day.
- 你说你活下来了，是么？ - 没错
- You said you survived this, right? - Yeah.
我给自己找到了父亲、领导者和老师
I found myself a father, a leader, a teacher.
只有直面死亡
You must meet death.
才能得以重生
in order to be reborn.
他救了我
He helped me.
癌症的解药是什么，埃里克？
What is the cure for cancer, Eric?
不珍惜生命的人不配拥有它
Those who don't appreciate life do not deserve life.
死亡的解药？
The cure for death itself?
就是永生
The answer is immortality.
丹尼！
Daniel!
留下一笔财富
By creating a legacy,
活了值得纪念的一生 你才能永生
by living a life worth remembering, you become immortal.
现在我们发现你坐在桌子的另一面了
So now you find the tables are turned.
他找的是你
He asked for you.
- 你他妈的到底要什么？ - 我告诉过你了
- What the fuck do you want? - I told you.
他想让我们活下去
He wants us to survive this.
我想做个游戏
I want to play a game.
你要按规则来
You have to play by the fucking rules!
规则很简单
The rules are simple.
你要做的只是… 坐在这里和我说话
All you have to do is sit here and talk to me.
什么？
What?
时间到了 你会发现你儿子
If you can do that long enough, you will find your son.
在一个安全的地方
in a safe and secure state.
那他妈的是什么？
What the fuck is that?
是你儿子丹尼 你还记得他吧？
It's your son, Daniel. You remember him, don't you?
我爸他…
My dad's a…
可不是好惹的
He's a real hardass.
我说你…
I call you unworthy.
配不上你被赋予的生命
of the life that you've been given.
你儿子垂死的消息…
The knowledge of your son's impending death.
促使你原谅了他所有的过错
has caused you to forgive all his sins.
为什么只有在性命攸关的时候… 我们才想起这么做？
Why is that we're only willing to do that when a life is at stake?
丹尼！
Daniel!
我不听你废话了
I'm done listening to you.
别忘了规则
Don't forget the rules.
闭嘴！
Shut the fuck up!
他在玩一个游戏
He's playing a game.
我不想和他废话了
I don't wanna talk to him.
你给我闭嘴
You're not saying shit.
我们都清楚你是哪种人
We both know the sort of person you are.
你儿子快死了…
I'd like to go now until your son is pissing…
我会把你带到屋子里去
I'll take you to the house.
丹尼？
Daniel?
埃里克，有些事我没告诉你
There's something I haven't told you, Eric.
约翰死了后，我会完成他未完成的工作
It is I who will carry on John's work after he dies.
丹尼！
Daniel!
随便你啊，毁了它
So go ahead. Destroy it.
而你…
And you…
丹尼！
Daniel!
…就是我第一个实验对象
…are my first test subject.
现在被锁上的你
Now you are locked away,
是那么的孤独和无助
helpless and alone.
- 你他妈的婊子 - 游戏结束
- You fucking bitch. - Game over.
我要杀了你他妈的！
I'll fucking kill you!
你个婊子！
You fucking bitch!
我要杀了你他妈的！
I'll fucking kill you!
不！
No!